<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>	
	<info>
		<name>Crossbreed Celestial/Fiend Race</name>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="race-crossbreed-celestial-fiend.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/inbabbini/roleanding-customs/main/sources/races/race-crossbreed-celestial-fiend.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Crossbreed Celestial/Fiend" type="Race" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_RACE_CROSSBREED_CELESTIAL_FIEND">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">You are the rare and impossible offspring of celestial and infernal bloodlines—a being whose very existence defies the cosmic war that has raged across the planes since time immemorial. Warred against by both sides and misunderstood by most, you must navigate a world that sees you as either abomination or curiosity. Within you burns the conflict of opposing natures, a constant struggle between divine light and hellish flame that shapes not only your appearance but your very soul.</p>
			<h4>MARKED BY CONTRADICTION</h4>
			<p>Your form stands as a physical testament to the impossible union of your parents. You are notably large and imposing—standing notably taller than humans, with a build of considerable strength. Your skin bears the marks of both your heritages: infernal darkness touched by celestial luminescence. Some features lean toward your demonic heritage—scaled limbs, fierce horns, or infernal resilience—while others reflect your celestial origin—radiant patterns, ethereal grace, or divine presence. Your appearance shifts subtly with your emotional state and internal struggles, your infernal and celestial natures constantly vying for dominance.</p>
			<p class="indent">Unlike those of purely infernal or celestial descent, you cannot hide or ignore one side of your nature. Both are integral to your being, and both demand to be acknowledged. This internal conflict is not merely philosophical—it manifests in your reactions, your capabilities, and sometimes in your very form.</p>
			<h4>AGELESS WITNESSES</h4>
			<p>Your celestial heritage grants you an unnaturally long lifespan—centuries may pass before age claims you naturally. This longevity transforms you into a repository of knowledge and experience. Where others accumulate decades, you gather centuries of memory, witnessing empires rise and fall, learning secrets that fade from mortal minds. This extended existence brings its own burden: watching companions age and perish, carrying the weight of ancient knowledge, and struggling with the perspective of one who has seen it all.</p>
			<h4>MANIFESTING DUALITY</h4>
			<p>You unlock the ability to fully embrace your dual nature through a technique called <strong>Duplicity</strong>. With focus and effort, you can separate your celestial and infernal aspects into two distinct physical forms, each embodying one side of your heritage. While separated, each manifestation retains half your hit points and can act independently, though they remain tethered (unable to stray more than 300 feet apart). This profound act of self-division can last up to an hour before your aspects are forced to reintegrate, and you must complete a short rest before attempting it again.</p>
			<h4>NAMES</h4>
			<p>Crossbreeds Celestial/Fiends may bear names from either of their heritages, or choose entirely new names reflecting their unique identity. Many favor names that hint at their duality or that speak to virtues or concepts they strive to embody.</p>
			<h4>CROSSBREED CELESTIAL/FIEND TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your unique heritage grants you the following racial traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Increase one ability score by 2 and a different ability score by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> You mature at a rate similar to humans, reaching adulthood in your late teens or early twenties. However, your celestial heritage grants you tremendous longevity. Natural death comes only after centuries have passed, giving you time to accumulate vast knowledge and wisdom.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Your dual nature does not predispose you toward any particular alignment, but the internal conflict you experience often leads toward extremes. Many struggle to find balance between their celestial and infernal impulses.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Your form is notably larger than humans, standing between 8 and 10 feet tall. Your size is Large.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Your infernal heritage grants you superior vision in darkness. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Longevity.</em></strong> Due to your centuries of existence, you have gained extensive knowledge and experience. You gain proficiency in two skills of your choice from the following: Insight, History, Religion, Deception, Intimidation, Persuasion, and Survival.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common, Infernal, and Celestial.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Duplicity.</em></strong> You have learned to manifest your dual nature physically, separating into two distinct entities. As a bonus action, you can split your form into your celestial and infernal aspects as two separate creatures within 5 feet of you.</p>
			<div class="indent">
				<p><strong>Manifestation Mechanics</strong> — Each manifestation retains half of your current hit points (rounded down) and can be controlled independently on your turn. Both share your action economy except for movement—each can move separately. Only one manifestation can concentrate on a spell at a time.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong>Tether:</strong> The two manifestations cannot move more than 300 feet apart. If they exceed this distance, they are forcibly drawn back together.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong>Reintegration:</strong> Your manifestations automatically reintegrate when either reaches 0 hit points, when you choose to (free action), or after the maximum duration expires. Once reintegrated, you cannot use Duplicity again until you finish a short rest.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong>Duration:</strong> You can maintain separation for up to 1 minute during combat, or 1 hour outside stressful situations.</p>
				<p><strong>Celestial Manifestation</strong> — Your celestial aspect gains advantage on Persuasion checks, resistance to being charmed or frightened, a protective aura granting allies within 5 feet advantage on saving throws against charm and fear effects, and prioritizes defending companions. It cannot access infernal-origin features or abilities.</p>
				<p><strong>Infernal Manifestation</strong> — Your infernal aspect gains advantage on Intimidation checks and checks to break or force objects, melee attacks deal an additional 1d4 fire damage, and prioritizes offensive action. It cannot access celestial-origin features or abilities or use defensive features that benefit allies.</p>
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d4">8'0"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_LARGE" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CROSSBREED_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DUPLICITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONGEVITY" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Increase" type="Racial Trait" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CROSSBREED_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE">
		<description>
			<p>You increase one ability score by 2 and a different ability score by 1.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_WOTC_GRANTS_DEFAULT_RACIAL_ASI" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Duplicity" type="Racial Trait" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DUPLICITY">
		<description>
			<p>You have learned to manifest your dual nature physically, separating into two distinct entities. As a bonus action, you can split your form into your celestial and infernal aspects as two separate creatures within 5 feet of you.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">MANIFESTATION MECHANICS</h5>
			<p>Each manifestation retains half of your current hit points (rounded down) and can be controlled independently on your turn. Both share your action economy except for movement—each can move separately. Only one manifestation can concentrate on a spell at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Tether:</strong> The two manifestations cannot move more than 300 feet apart. If they exceed this distance, they are forcibly drawn back together.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Reintegration:</strong> Your manifestations automatically reintegrate when either reaches 0 hit points, when you choose to (free action), or after the maximum duration expires. Once reintegrated, you cannot use Duplicity again until you finish a short rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Duration:</strong> You can maintain separation for up to 1 minute during combat, or 1 hour outside stressful situations.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">CELESTIAL MANIFESTATION</h5>
			<p>Your celestial aspect gains the following benefits:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled indent">
				<li><strong>Persuasion Mastery:</strong> Advantage on Persuasion checks.</li>
				<li><strong>Emotional Fortitude:</strong> Resistance to being charmed or frightened.</li>
				<li><strong>Protective Aura:</strong> Allies within 10 feet of your celestial manifestation gain advantage on saving throws against charm and fear effects.</li>
				<li><strong>Ally Defense Priority:</strong> This manifestation prioritizes defending and protecting companions.</li>
				<li><strong>Restriction:</strong> Cannot access infernal-origin features or abilities.</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">INFERNAL MANIFESTATION</h5>
			<p>Your infernal aspect gains the following benefits:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled indent">
				<li><strong>Intimidation Mastery:</strong> Advantage on Intimidation checks and checks to break or force objects.</li>
				<li><strong>Fiery Strikes:</strong> Your melee attacks deal an additional 1d4 fire damage.</li>
				<li><strong>Aggressive Focus:</strong> Cannot use defensive features that benefit allies; prioritizes offensive action.</li>
				<li><strong>Restriction:</strong> Cannot access celestial-origin features or abilities.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>Split into celestial &amp; infernal manifestations (5 ft apart) with half your HP each, independent movement, 300-ft tether. Shared action economy except movement, only one can concentrate. Celestial: Persuasion advantage, charm/fear resist, ally resist 10ft aura. Infernal: Intimidation and breaking advantage, melee +1d4 fire damage. Duration: 1 min (combat) or 1 hour (non-combat).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Longevity" type="Racial Trait" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONGEVITY">
		<description>
			<p>Your centuries of existence have provided you with extensive knowledge and learning. You gain proficiency in two skills of your choice from the following list: Insight, History, Religion, Deception, Intimidation, Persuasion, and Survival.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Longevity)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
