<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<element name="Mateador" type="Feat" source="Custom" id="ID_FEAT_MATEADOR">
		<description>
			<p>You have mastered the ancestral art of mate infusion, using carefully selected herbs and preparation techniques to create beverages with powerful beneficial effects.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mate Preparation.</em></strong> While taking a short or long rest, you can prepare a mate round. You must have access to special herbs and water to do so. Each mate round can benefit up to {{proficiency}} creatures. Each effect has its own duration and requirements.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Material Components.</em></strong> Preparing mate requires special herbs and ingredients. Your DM determines the cost and availability of these materials.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Multiple Rounds.</em></strong> Only one effect can be active at a time. If you prepare one round while another is active, the previous round's effect ends.</p>            
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mate Effects.</em></strong> When a round is consumed, you choose one of the following effects for all creatures:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled indent">
				<li><strong>Restoration.</strong> The creature gains the effect of a <i>Lesser Restoration</i> spell.</li>
				<li><strong>Vitality.</strong> The creature can use a number of hit dice equal to your proficiency bonus. They roll the dice and heal accordingly.</li>
				<li><strong>Fortune.</strong> The creature has advantage on ability checks or saving throw of the Skill(checks) or Ability(ST) for 1 hour.</li>
				<li><strong>Inspiration.</strong> The creature gains the effects of Bless for 1 hour.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Short Rest">
			<description>Prepare a round of mate using special herbs affecting up to {{proficiency}} creatures. Each creature gains: Lesser Restoration, or {{proficiency}} Hit Dice, or advantage on 1 ability skill checks or 1 ability saving throws (1 hr), or Bless effect (1 hr). Requires special material components.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
