<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Hellish Knight Archetype</name>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="class-fighter-archetype-hellish-knight.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/inbabbini/roleanding-customs/main/sources/classes/class-fighter-archetype-hellish-knight.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<!-- Hellish Knight Archetype -->
	<element name="Hellish Knight" type="Archetype" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_HELLISH_KNIGHT">
		<supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Hellish Knight represents a fusion of martial mastery and infernal power, a fighter trained in the ancient ways of the demonic legions. Those who adopt this archetype combine devastating melee combat with the ability to channel infernal flames, becoming warriors whose very presence radiates heat and danger. Unlike traditional spellcasters, the Hellish Knight weaves fire magic into their fighting style, treating spellcasting as an extension of their combat prowess.</p>
			<div element="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_PYROMANTIC_SPELLCASTING"/>
			<div element="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_MIDAS_TOUCH"/>
			<div element="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_BOND"/>
			<div element="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_PRESENCE"/>
			<div element="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_SENTINEL"/>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>A warrior forged in the fires of the infernal planes, blending martial combat with pyromantic magic and infernal techniques.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_PYROMANTIC_SPELLCASTING" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_MIDAS_TOUCH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_BOND" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_PRESENCE" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_SENTINEL" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- 3rd Level: Hellish Knight -->
    <element name="Hellish Knight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_PYROMANTIC_SPELLCASTING">
        <description>
            <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the ability to cast spells—but only fire-based spells—drawn from the infernal traditions. You channel the flames of the Nine Hells through your martial focus.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Cantrips.</em></strong> You learn two cantrips of your choice from the pyromantic spell list. You learn an additional pyromantic cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spell Slots.</em></strong> The Hellish Knight table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your pyromantic spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells Known of 1st-Level and Higher.</em></strong> You know three 1st-level pyromantic spells of your choice. The Hellish Knight table shows when you learn more pyromantic spells of 1st level or higher. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the pyromantic spells you know with another spell of your choice from the pyromantic spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spellcasting Ability.</em></strong> Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your pyromantic spells. You use your Wisdom modifier whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. Additionally, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a pyromantic spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <center>
                <p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                <p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            </center>
            <h5 class="caption">FIRE ABSORPTION</h5>
            <p>As an action, you can absorb and extinguish all flames in a 15-foot-radius sphere centered on yourself. This ability allows you to consume fire and fuel your infernal essence, though the exact benefits remain to be determined as your mastery grows.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HELLISH KNIGHT SPELLCASTING</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-10">Fighter Level</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4th</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>3</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>3</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>3</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>3</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>3</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>3</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>3</td><td>13</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>You have the ability to cast spells, mostly fire-based.</description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Hellish Knight" ability="Wisdom" prepare="false" allowReplace="true">
            <list>((Wizard,(Evocation||Abjuration))||Pyromantic)</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_THIRD" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="3" />
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="4" />
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="7" />
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="10" />
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="13" />
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="16" />
            <stat name="hellish knight:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="19" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 1" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Hellish Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" spellcasting="Hellish Knight" />
        </rules>
    </element>

	<!-- 3rd Level: Midas Touch -->
	<element name="Midas Touch" type="Archetype Feature" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_MIDAS_TOUCH">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you learn the infernal technique of manipulating inert materials—particularly metals—allowing you to reshape them to your will. This ancient practice is perfected by demonic weapon-smiths and masters of infernal warfare.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">CONTINUOUS MANIPULATION LIMITS</h5>
			<p>You can maintain up to your proficiency bonus objects continuously under the effects of Midas Touch. The total material you can manipulate is limited to {{proficiency}} square meters.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Infernal Forge (Ritual)</h5>
			<p>You can perform a ritual to fundamentally reshape metal or metallic objects. This ritual requires a short rest of continuous contact with the object. The object's shape, weight distribution, and configuration can be altered while preserving its overall function and material composition. As long as you maintain continuous contact, the effect persists. If you break contact, the modifications revert to their original state within 1 minute, depending on the extent of the reconfiguration.</p>
			<p>While under the effect of Infernal Forge, you can:</p>
            <ul class="unstyled indent">
                <li>Resize an object to fit your personal use</li>
                <li>Alter the structural form of an object (within reason)</li>
                <li>Assimilate metallic objects into another object under this effect</li>
                <li>Anchor the object so it cannot be stolen or disarmed</li>
            </ul>
			<h5 class="caption">Transfiguration (Instantaneous)</h5>
			<p>As a bonus action, you can temporarily reshape a metal object or weapon you're touching. This most effects require concentration and lasts up to 10 minutes. You can use Transfiguration a number of times equal to {{proficiency}} per long rest. Choose one of the following effects:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled indent">
				<li><strong>Iron Sphere (Reaction, requires shield).</strong> Expand your shield into a perfect metal sphere. Gain +5 AC until the end of your next turn.</li>
				<li><strong>Solidification (Bonus action, requires armor).</strong> Prepare to receive incoming damage. Your movement becomes 0. Attacks against you have disadvantage until the start of your next turn.</li>
				<li><strong>Extend (Bonus action, requires melee weapon).</strong> Extend your weapon's reach by 5 feet.</li>
				<li><strong>Colossal (Bonus action, requires weapon).</strong> Increase size and density of your weapon. Add 1d4 damage equal to the weapon's damage type to melee attacks.</li>
				<li><strong>Metal Curtain (Action, requires shield).</strong> Expand your shield into a wall of metal. Create a 15-foot-by-10-foot wall. While concentrating, you can use your bonus action to move it with you up to half your movement speed.</li>
				<li><strong>Modify Object (Action, no tool required).</strong> Temporarily change the basic shape of a mostly metallic object that isn't magical.</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">Craftmanship</h5> 
            <p>You gain proficiency in smith's tools if you don't already have it. You can use Midas Touch to create or repair metal items during downtime.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Proficiency per Long Rest">
			<description>Maintain up to {{proficiency}} objects under Midas manipulation (total {{proficiency}} square meters). Infernal Forge: Short rest ritual, resizes/reshapes metal objects, effects revert 1 min after contact breaks. Transfiguration: Bonus action, concentration, choose from Iron Sphere (Shield), Solidification (BA Dodge), Extend (C, Reach), Colossal (C,+1d4), Metal Curtain (C), or Modify Object (C).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- 7th Level: Infernal Bond -->
	<element name="Infernal Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_BOND">
		<description>
			<p>At 7th level, your connection to infernal power deepens. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Fire Mastery.</em></strong> You have resistance to fire damage. Additionally, when you cast a spell that deals fire damage, you add your spellcasting ability modifier ({{wisdom:modifier}}) to the damage rolled.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hellish Presence.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can manifest an aura of flames around your body for 1 minute. While this aura is active, any creature that starts its turn within 5 feet of you takes fire damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum 1). You can dismiss the aura early. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Proficiency per Long Rest">
			<description>Fire resistance. Add your spellcasting ability modifier ({{wisdom:modifier}}) to fire spell damage. Hellish Presence aura: 5-ft radius, ability modifier ({{wisdom:modifier}}) fire damage per turn, 1 minute duration.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- 10th Level: Infernal Presence -->
	<element name="Infernal Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_PRESENCE">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, the infernal power coursing through you becomes visible to all. Your very presence becomes an extension of your combat mastery.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">BLAZING AURA</h5>
			<p>Your Hellish Presence aura can now activate at no action cost. Additionally, the aura's damage radius increases to 10 feet, and creatures that are immune to fire take half damage from the aura instead of being immune to it in this context.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">INFERNAL RESILIENCE</h5>
			<p>When you finish a short rest, you can spend Hit Die and regain hit points as you draw infernal energy from nearby flames, campfires, torches, or other fire sources (even if you created them with a spell). Add your Wisdom modifier ({{wisdom:modifier}}) to each hit die result restored this way if a fire source was consumed for the die. Additionally, you gain temporary hit points equal to your proficiency bonus ({{proficiency}}) at the start of each turn while your Hellish Presence aura is active, losing them when the aura ends.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Hellish Presence activation at no cost (10-ft radius). Creatures with fire immunity take half damage from aura. On short rest, spent Hit Die regain HP + {{wisdom:modifier}} if a nearby flame is consumed for the die. Gain {{proficiency}} temp HP each turn while aura active, lose them when aura ends.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- 15th Level: Infernal Sentinel -->
	<element name="Infernal Sentinel" type="Archetype Feature" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELLISH_KNIGHT_INFERNAL_SENTINEL">
		<description>
			<p>At 15th level, your mastery of infernal combat reaches its apex, and you become a sentinel of hellish power on the battlefield.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">OPPORTUNITY ATTACK MASTERY</h5>
			<p>When you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, that creature's speed is reduced to 0 until the end of the current turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you even when they take the Disengage action before leaving your reach.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">PROTECTIVE REACTION</h5>
			<p>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you and that target is within 5 feet of you (and that target does not have this ability), you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against the attacking creature.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">IMPROVED FIRE MASTERY</h5>
			<p>When you hit a creature with a melee attack and that creature takes fire damage from you as a result of your action on the same turn, that creature has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes against the first fire-based spell before the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>Opportunity attacks reduce target's speed to 0 until end of turn. Creatures provoke opportunity attacks even with Disengage. Reaction: make melee attack when creature attacks ally within 5 feet. Fire-damaged creatures by your attacks have disadvantage on next fire-based spell save until end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
