<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<!-- Red-Flame Blade -->
	<element name="Red-Flame Blade" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_RED_FLAME_BLADE">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one creature within the spell's range, otherwise the spell fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack's normal effects, and red fire leaps from the target to a different creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of it. The second creature takes fire damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
			<p class="indent">This spell's damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra 1d8 fire damage to the target, and the fire damage to the second creature increases to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. Both damage rolls increase by 1d8 at 11th level and 17th level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="range">5 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a weapon</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Explosive Jumps -->
	<element name="Explosive Jumps" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_EXPLOSIVE_JUMPS">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your jumping distance is tripled as you conjure fiery explosions from your feet and palms that propel you in the air.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">explosive, fire, movement, transmutation</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="components">V, S</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="text">Your jumping distance is tripled as you conjure fiery explosions from your feet and palms that propel you in the air.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Explosive Step -->
	<element name="Explosive Step" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_EXPLOSIVE_STEP">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You conjure a fiery ball and detonate it near yourself to propel you into the air, targeting a landing space you can see up to 30 feet away.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">explosive, fire, movement, conjuration</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="components">V</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="text">You conjure a fiery ball and detonate it near yourself to propel you into the air, targeting a landing space you can see up to 30 feet away.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Scorching Earth -->
	<element name="Scorching Earth" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_SCORCHING_EARTH">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose a point you can see on the ground within range. A fire geyser erupts in a 20-foot cube centered on that point. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d12 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Additionally, the ground in that area becomes difficult terrain until cleared away. Each 5-foot-square portion of the area requires at least 1 minute to clear by hand.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d12 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">damage, area, fire, earth, difficult terrain, transmutation</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="components">V, S, M (a piece of coal)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="text">Choose a point you can see on the ground within range. A fire geyser erupts in a 20-foot cube centered on that point. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 3d12 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The ground becomes difficult terrain until cleared (1 minute per 5-foot square).

At Higher Levels: Increase damage by 1d12 for each slot level above 3rd.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Fire Form -->
	<element name="Fire Form" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_FIRE_FORM">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Thin and wispy flames wreathe your body for the duration, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack, the flames erupt. The attacker takes 2d8 fire damage. In addition, whenever you attack a creature with a melee attack, the creature takes 2d8 additional fire damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">damage, fire, reaction, evocation</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="components">V, S, M (a bit of phosphorus or a firefly)</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="text">Thin and wispy flames wreathe your body, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.

Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack, the flames erupt and the attacker takes 2d8 fire damage. Whenever you attack a creature with a melee attack, the creature takes 2d8 additional fire damage.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Fire Syphon -->
	<element name="Fire Syphon" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_FIRE_SYPHON">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When a creature casts a spell or makes an attack that would deal fire damage, and the caused effect is inside your range, you can attempt to absorb the fire damage caused by it, negating it.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the creature casts a spell of the same level you cast this spell or lower, you negate the fire damage. If it is higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + spell level; on a success, the fire damage is negated.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the creature makes an attack or creates an area of effect that would deal fire damage, you roll the save or take the hit. If you either pass the save or the attack misses you, the whole fire damage of the attack is negated.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">reaction, damage, fire, abjuration</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you can take when you see a creature within 60 feet of you making an attack or casting a spell that would create fire</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="components">S</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="text">When a creature casts a spell or makes an attack that would deal fire damage within range, you can attempt to absorb the fire caused by it.

If the creature casts a spell of the same level you cast this spell or lower, you negate the fire damage. If it is higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability (DC = 10 + spell level). On a success, the fire damage is negated.

If the creature makes an attack or creates an area of effect dealing fire damage, you can attempt a save. If you pass the save or the attack misses, the whole fire damage is negated.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Fiery Weapon -->
	<element name="Fiery Weapon" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_FIERY_WEAPON">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a weapon and imbue it with fiery energy. Until the spell ends, it emits bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light in an additional 20 feet. In addition, it becomes a magic weapon and weapon attacks made with it deal an extra 2d8 fire damage on a hit for the duration.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one additional weapon for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">damage, fire, weapon, evocation</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="components">V, S</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="text">You touch a weapon and imbue it with fiery energy. Until the spell ends, it emits bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. It becomes a magic weapon and weapon attacks made with it deal an extra 2d8 fire damage on a hit.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one additional weapon for each slot level above 3rd.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Flame Strike -->
	<element name="Flame Strike" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A vertical column of brilliant fire roars down from above. Each creature in a 10-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d6 fire damage and 4d6 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, both the fire damage and the radiant damage increase by 1d6 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">damage, area, fire, radiant, evocation</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="components">V, S, M (a pinch of sulfur)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="text">A vertical column of brilliant fire roars down from above. Each creature in a 10-foot-radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d6 fire damage and 4d6 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, both the fire damage and the radiant damage increase by 1d6 for each slot level above 4th.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Exploding Flames -->
	<element name="Exploding Flames" type="Spell" source="Custom" id="ID_SPELL_EXPLODING_FLAMES">
		<supports>Wizard, Sorcerer, Pyromantic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When another creature casts a fire-based spell, makes an attack, or otherwise creates an area of effect that deals fire damage within range, you can use your reaction to infuse that fire with your own fiery energy, violently expanding the flames created.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you do so, the caster of the fire effect has the option to reroll a number of fire damage dice equal to your spellcasting ability modifier. They must use the new values whether they are higher or lower. Additionally, if the fire effect required a saving throw, creatures making that save do so at disadvantage. If the fire effect was an attack roll, that attack is made with advantage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire, reaction, transmutation, support</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you can take when another creature casts, attacks, or creates fire-based area of effect</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="components">S</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="text">When another creature casts a fire-based spell, makes an attack, or creates an area of effect that deals fire damage within range, you can use your reaction to infuse that fire with your own fiery energy, violently expanding the flames created.

The caster of the fire effect has the option to reroll a number of fire damage dice equal to your spellcasting ability modifier. They must use the new values. If the fire effect required a saving throw, creatures making that save do so at disadvantage. If the fire effect was an attack roll, that attack is made with advantage.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell at 2nd level or higher, you can reroll 2 additional dice for each level above 1st.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
