<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Items - Shields</name>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="items-shields.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/inbabbini/roleanding-customs/main/sources/items/items-shields.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
<!-- Menmonite Shield +2 -->
	<element name="Menmonite Shield +2" type="Magic Item" source="Roleanding Customs" id="ID_CUSTOM_ITEM_ESCUDO_MENMONITA">
		<description>
			<p>This magical shield is remarkably powerful, granting a +2 bonus to AC. It bears the craftsmanship of infernal artificers and seems to hum with contained power.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">DEPLOYMENT</h5>
			<p>As a reaction, when you or an ally within 5 feet of you is targeted by a ranged attack or a damaging area effect, you can expand the shield to cover a wider area. Targets you choose within 5 feet of you gain half cover against ranged attacks, or +2 to their saving throws against the area effect until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">VIBRANIUM CORE</h5>
			<p>The material of this shield is incredibly resistant to impacts, absorbing nearly all the force of blows. You are immune to being knocked prone or pushed by attacks.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">SHOCKWAVE</h5>
			<p>As an action, you can activate the magnetic mechanism of this shield to slam its layers together, generating a shockwave in a 15-foot cone in front of you. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC 21). On a failed save, a creature is thrown 25 feet backward and knocked prone. If it strikes an obstacle, it takes 3d6 bludgeoning damage. This shield has 3 charges and regains 1d4 - 1 charges when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
            <set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>